There is a YouTuber named Venk.  It is quite famous.
Runs a tech channel.  He bought a new
car Mahindra XUV 9 which is the flagship
electric car from Mahindra.
He bought this car for ₹33 lakh
and was going on a trip with his friends.
While going, there was a hairpin
U turn on the way and at the time of the U turn,
a man came in the opposite lane.
Which came right in front of him.  The car
collided and fell into the ditch.   The
car was quite strong.  It was very good that
he did not suffer any injury or scratch.  But you
can find out by looking at the photos and videos
that the car is a total loss.  Mahindra
neglected it.  The insurance company neglected.
His words were completely dismissed.  The
car that should have been a total loss was
made to be repaired.   The
car came out after repair and there are
many issues inside the car.  This is the story
of a famous Uber who has reach all over the world.  There
is a kind of army all over the world to get support behind you.   There are a lot of
resources.  What if this
story was about a common man too?  Another latest
news came out that a fire broke out inside Mahindra's Be6.  While
moving, the car stopped and after
stopping, a fire broke out inside it.  At the same time,
Bwadi Seal is being recalled
due to issues arising in its battery.
All this is happening in the EV
scene today.  I
want to give you a detailed explanation about all this and
I have a message related to all this.  You will like
watching today's video in detail.
Without wasting any time
let's get rolling.  So Guys was the first thing that came to my
mind once.  I was
watching Mr. Sundarap's video on
why he bought his GLA 200D?  And the thing is that
when I was watching his video,
he discussed in between that he
wanted to buy BMW's X1 Electric.  And at
such a time it came to my mind that he is
an automobile journalist.  He is
very well informed about cars.  So when
they get all these packages in BMW, they
can get them in Mahindra at a much lower cost.  Then
why were they attracted towards BMW?  But
after watching today's video completely, you will also
see the sense in this.  So guys,
if I talk about Venk, there is a YouTuber named Venk,
when his car
met with such an accident, it was clear after looking at the car
that it was going to be a total loss.
Mahindra insisted on total loss of the car and the
insurance company absolutely insisted
that we will repair it.  On the other hand, it was very
difficult for Mahindra dealership to repair such a complex car, let alone touch it.  But still he
pushed himself.  Forced that car to be repaired.  I got
parts from here and there and added them together.
When a new car comes from Mahindra, it already has so many
niggles in it.
We did an ownership review of the XUV 9.
You can go here and see.  We had already
mentioned that many issues like software
related issues, wiring issues as well as
feature issues keep coming up.  So
how many issues will arise inside a repaired car.  The same
question was in Venom Tech's
mind as well.  He said no, this
car should be declared a total loss.  Don't repair it.
But still he had to lose.  After
giving a commitment of 1 month, he spent 5 months and brought
misery to that man.  He was chased and
called to the showroom again and again and
in the end, he was given a worn out car
and such a car was given which neither had any
kind of paint quality nor any kind
of fit finish.  Now
what do we get to know here?  Here we came
to know that the brand was insisted
that you repair the car.  The insurance was
insisted that you repair the car.
But because the product made by Mahindra
is born electric.  It
is completely newly developed.  The staff of the car company, the
staff of its dealership, are not capable enough to
repair such a car.
This capability or this
kind of knowledge has not yet been given to them so that
they can understand that thing properly.
So this is where I understood
why Mr. Sundardeep ji was preferring X1
over a Mahindra?  Reason being
X1, when they made their car electric, then
their staff, even though it was
not a born electric car, still their staff
is very well trained to solve
any kind of problem to repair or fix that car properly,
you will not get to see these things in Mahindra
and at the same time
you will
not get to see these things in any other manufacturer unless they are ready and have a lot of
experience in totally born electric cars, this is the same
thing we discussed when we were making this review
of XUV 9 that the owner used to
say that Tata has more experience in
making electric cars as compared to
Mahindra, hence you should choose such cars from a
company which has a lot of experience in the matter of electric.
Look, you don't care about the car.  You are
also concerned about his/her well-being.  You also have to be concerned with how the
car will stay with you,
not just
how the product is today and what it won't be tomorrow.
If you are not able to make sense of what I am saying then what I mean
to say is that buying a
Vin makes more sense and buying a BYD makes more sense rather than
buying a Creta
electric and a Tata's electric and
a Mahindra's electric.  Not just Indian
brands, if you are buying an electric product from any other brand, then
how strong their background is regarding their
product matters a lot
because in the long run, otherwise you will remain
just a handful pick on which
testing and RAD is being done.  If there is any
problem in your car, your car will be seized and
repaired.  Like BYD has also started
doing it now.  BYD is having
issues with the battery inside the seal.  It is being recalled
and given back after repair.
This is happening because
they can easily afford this thing.
This thing can be understood because they have been
making electric cars for so long.
He did not wake up today or tomorrow and
start making it.  If Mahindra, Tata
and other manufacturers, for
example Honda, bring an electric car, then
you will definitely see this issue in it too.
Now I would like to talk
about our second topic which is the
fire inside DE6.  Look guys,
many people had also told me in the comments
that you should talk about this.
Many people had said this on Instagram also.  But
as much as I studied about it, I will
tell you the simple thing.  The issue inside that car was
that the tyre of that car was totally
deflated.  Now one more thing I have to
say is that very low profile
tyres have been provided inside the Be6.  And
according to Indians, according to Indian roads,
I don't think those tyres were that
suitable.  Now those tyres were totally depleted.  There was
absolutely no air inside them.
Despite that, the owner drove it for 10 to 15 minutes
due to which the tyre burst.  It started getting very
hot.  The
tyre caught fire due to end heat.  Now see, this
is possible because the weight of the car is
very high.  It is a 2100 kg car.  So
if there is a heavy SUV weighing 2100 kg then there is a
lot of load on its tyres.   In
such a situation, if you search on Google,
you will see that there are
high chances that a car tyre may
catch fire.  Also, the
tyres of electric cars are made of a slightly softer
compound because they have to
bear more stress than a
petrol or diesel car.  So they are more
lightly to get fired and to get more heated
up.  That's why there was a fire inside Be6.  There is
no issue of S Sach Mahindra inside it.
He also issued a statement
that there was no issue with the motor and battery.
Even though there was a fire inside the body, both things were intact.  This makes it clear
that some things are okay.
But I want to discuss with you in this video
that if you are considering an electric car for yourself, then
I would say take a step back and
try to move towards a better product.
For example, if you go for BMW's X1, it will
provide you more value in the long run.  Because there is a lot of competition among the new companies
that are making new products.
He
is not that established in this particular
product line.  At the same time,
when established companies
make such products, they have a
lot of marketing behind it and the resale
value is high.  What will happen with this?  If
you buy X1, you will get better resale value
compared to buying a Ginny pickup car in
which everything inside is newly made.
Guys this was my opinion and my
belief on electric cars and this is why I
somehow feel like electric
cars will fail in India.
How much do you agree with my opinion?  How much do you disagree
?  You can tell me in the comment section.
Also I feel like
this question is arising in my mind that should you
spend so much on any other brand.
Now I understand when people
say we won't buy Invicto.
Because we don't want to pay ₹30 lakh for a
Suzuki just like people don't want to pay
₹40 lakh for a Mahindra.  In such a situation, you
would want to get a better brand.
Get a better brand value that will support you later.
Now if you have a Mahindra car worth ₹1 lakh,
then you will get service as per a car worth ₹1 lakh.
But the same
Mahindra dealership
may not be able to provide you with the same service as a ₹40 lakh car.  I have
now totally agreed that you
cannot buy a car just by looking at the product.
You also need to look at the brand and brand value.
Tell me what you think in the comment section.
What do you think about electric cars?  And
if you haven't seen the donut video, a solid state
battery that looks totally like the future.  It will be
fully charged within 5 minutes and will run
approximately 600 km in one go.  It can run and the
most interesting thing is that you get 1 lakh life cycles.  If you
want to know about all this,
whether it is real or how this battery
is made, then you can go here and see.  This is what was
inside this video.  See you in the next
one.  Until then stay smart.
[music]
P